so you're considering moving to Central
Texas particularly the areas of bell
Corel and L passes County here are the
five things to consider before making
your move hi and welcome to my channel
I'm Andrea dudic realtor and Associate
broker with fista real estate now before
we dive in I want to tell you a little
bit about where I'm from so that you can
understand my transition here and what
that experience was like for me I'm
originally from Las Vegas Nevada so in
some ways a lot of the climate and
weather are comparable but there were a
lot of things that I had to adjust to in
moving here now don't get me wrong there
is nowhere else that I would rather be
but you do want to consider these things
before you head here for now let's get
into the five key factors to consider
number one the
weather when it's hot it's really hot
when it's cold it is really cold but in
reality you're going to have those I
think Stark differences in weather no
matter where you go here you really have
three really hot months and but the
spring times are beautiful and as you
can see here we have Belton Lake behind
me there's so many hiking trails and
just beautiful outdoor things to do that
you might not get in other places number
two the bugs there are a lot of bugs and
they are very large think scorpions
wasps spiders mosquitoes and termites
now living somewhere where you get this
is totally worth it I mean if you have
water you're probably going to have
mosquitoes termites are a thing here
whenever a buyer does a home purchase
it's recommended that they get a wood
destroying insect inspection so that
they can check for things like termites
and it can be treated and remedied
scorpions they're pretty gross but are
these the type of bugs that are going to
pre prevent me from moving somewhere
where the culture is fantastic and the
environment provides everything you
could want for your family no we have
Solutions for all of that number three
property taxes we have a lot of people
coming from out of the area California
New York maybe Florida and I think a lot
of people assume that because our house
prices are so low that their payments
are going to be that low as well but we
actually have really high property taxes
compared to a lot of other places one of
the caveats to that and well one of the
benefits is that we don't have income
tax and so you're saving there whereas
you're getting property higher property
taxes what also benefits people is that
there are exemptions to help save you on
those property taxes homestead exemption
you've got disabled vet exemptions over
65 so those are going to save you a lot
of money in terms of your property taxes
if you claim those things and there are
plenty of services that will help you re
you know fight property taxes and do
things to reduce your payments number
four
allergies I think wherever you go there
are probably going to be allergens in
that area here some of our top allergens
are grass pollen Ragweed Cedar and mold
I particularly was not real affected
by allergens when I got here um I think
that's just going to be particular to
the person but vadil they have allergy
shots and they might not even bother you
at all they are seasonal and so some
Seasons might be a little more tricky
than others but it's worth it especially
if you're loving where you're at number
five tornadoes this is probably the
thing that I hear people are most scared
about when moving to Texas
um it's not super common to have a
really serious tornado my husband's been
here over 40 years or just at 40 years
and he just experienced our first
notable tornado so again not super
common I've been here eight years and
that was the first one I'll do a whole
other video on that but generally while
there are a lot of tornadoes throughout
Texas they are not super common and
there are precautions while a tornado
did cause some damage there were no
fatalities and honestly the community
response was so heartwarming I'll be
sharing more about that in an upcoming
video ultimately cultural and
environmental factors are huge deciding
factors when moving to an area to me the
culture and the values of of this
community far outweighed any sort of
risks or deterrence that um I may have
had in coming here and moving to the
central Texas area was one of the best
decisions of my life and I hope it's one
of yours if you want to discuss your
move or if you have any questions about
the area i' love to speak with you feel
free to reach me via text call email or
Zoom you can find all my contact
information below don't forget to
subscribe to my channel and hit the Bell
icon so you can be the first to know
about all the things happening in
Central Texas